Give thanks to God.
A brother there - you have this spirit upon you.
The brother in this line here.
Can I help you?
I see you sitting down. You are sitting down.
Yes.
Can I help you?
You have that spirit of man.
He's a gay. He is confessing he's a gay.
Don't worry. The name you called him is not the name God gave to me.
So we are not calling that name here.
We call it 'spirit of man'.
He has the spirit of man.
Ok.
My throat!
Come out, look here!
Look here!
Deliverance In Jesus' Name
Out!
Since morning, he refused to stand up.
We have been praying.
The four times I looked in that direction, I asked, "Who is this man?" He refused to stand up.
He kept looking at what we are doing.
I was asking God, "Is he an armed robber?" I could not hear anything.
The Lord said, "No, he has the spirit of man".
He does not agree with what we are doing here.
He has been sitting down since morning; he refused to stand up.
I said, "Come, can I help you? You have the spirit of man". He came out to say he is this.
It is gone.
Next Sunday, when he comes out - there is nothing like that again.
He's free.
Set Free In Jesus' Name
TESTIMONY CONTINUES
Right now, the young man in question is here in our midst
to share his testimony to the Glory of God Almighty.
Remember, we are giving this testimony to the shame of the devil and the Glory of God.
We believe you will be educated and enlightened concerning how Jesus Christ is setting people free,
as you listen to his confession and testimony right now.
For the benefit of our viewers, our brother is not going to be speaking in English.
He's going to be speaking in a local dialect which will be translated for the benefit of everyone.
So, brother, you are very welcome here today. Please introduce yourself to us.
Testimony Time
Mr Patrick James (Tanzania)
He says his name is Patrick James and he comes from Tanzania.
So tell us brother, what was the prophecy you received last week here at The SCOAN?
Mr Patrick (Prophecy Testimony)
The prophecy that I received that day, happened like this: The Prophet called me and I hid myself.
He called me again and I hid myself once again.
Then, I told my neighbour that he was speaking to him but my neighbour said it was me.
When I came out, he prophesied that I had the spirit of man inside me.
He said that last week, when he was in the service, the man of God called him out and pointed to him.
He said, "You, come to me".
When the man of God said that, he told his neighbour, "The man of God is speaking to you.
Why don't you stand up?" Without knowing that the man of God was referring to him.
Then, the man of God said, "No, it's not the other person. But it's you".
He then stood up and went to the man of God.
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
That spirit started to strangle me, and I felt something like an arrow hit my chest.
It strangled me to such an extent that I could neither talk nor pray.
He said that when the man of God pointed to him and said he has the spirit of man,
immediately, he started moving to the man of God, and that's when he started feeling something poking
in his chest and also something started to hook his neck.
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
When the man of God prayed for me, the spirit released me immediately.
He said that when he went to the man of God, the man of God stretched his hand and prayed for him.
Immediately the man of God prayed for him in the name of Jesus Christ, that's when the thing that was
hooking him, left him immediately.
Glory be to God Almighty! Let us put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
So, right now brother, can you please tell us how this word of prophecy is true for your life?
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
It is very true. When I was ten years old in primary school,
one old man who was my neighbour called me one day.
He enticed me with chips, biscuits and other things to come to him and later, he raped me.
He said that it is true what the man of God told him.
Because when he was a young child of 10 years,
a man met him and forced himself on him by enticing him with sweets and things like that when he was
coming back from school.
That is when the man forced himself on him and started to sleep with him.
So from there, he started having the urge for men.
Since that day, the spirit of man entered me, and I felt like I was a lady.
When that spirit entered me, I saw myself sleeping in the ocean and I was a very beautiful lady -
more beautiful than all the women on earth.
Then, I didn't want to sleep with women anymore. I had the urge to sleep with men like me.
He said that ever since then he had a strong urge for men
and he never had an urge for women.
He started seeing himself in his dreams as a beautiful, very beautiful woman
and his attraction was towards men and not women anymore.
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
As I continued like that I later dropped out of school.
I later moved from Arusha to the Mwanza region.
There, I continued sleeping with men for 15 years.
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
He said that since the age of 10 years, he has been sleeping with men.
He changed his habits. He even stopped school and had to shift from the region in which he was
to another region. When he went there, he continued his habit of sleeping with men.
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
All the years that I was there, I continued with this habit of sleeping with men.
Until I met a lady called Mary who asked me, "When are you going to stop doing this?"
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
He said that he engaged in this for almost 15 years until he met one lady called Mary.
This lady asked him how long he would continue doing this.
Before you get to that area, brother, can you just explain to us what your lifestyle was like
during this period, after that spirit of man had entered you, right from the age of 10.
What were the type of things you found yourself doing that you know are not ordinary for you to do as a man?
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
I used to use expensive creams and apply different makeup, including lip gloss.
I used to apply eyeliner and thicken my eyebrows.
Whenever I entered a place, I would catwalk and act seductively, like a lady or a model.
He said that he used to put cream on his face, bleach himself and put lipstick on.
Even when he was walking, he would walk like a lady - wherever he was.
You would think that a lady is sitting there - not a man.
He would catwalk in front of people as if he was a lady.
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
I continued acting like a lady until I reached a point where I could no longer understand myself.
I was not attracted to women at all.
He said that he continued being like a lady, wearing tight clothes.
At the end of the day, he didn't love women anymore; he was just forcing himself on men.
I became infamous and started going from one region to another to sleep with men.
I was moving around every corner from Dar es Salaam, to Mwanza, to Arusha,
sleeping with all kinds of men.
He said that he started going from one region to another.
He now started developing the habit of sleeping with big men.
He used to sleep with men who are working in the government. People who have honours.
He continued developing this to such an extent that he became like a professional in what he was doing.
Ok. You said initially at the age of 10, you began seeing yourself in the dream as a woman.
Can you just explain more about those dreams that you were having right from that initial time
when a man raped you at the age of 10. How did these dreams continue?
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
I used to dream of being a very beautiful lady; there was no woman as beautiful as me.
He said that he used to see himself as the most beautiful, unimaginably gorgeous lady in his dreams.
Whenever he saw himself, he had this unimaginable beauty.
As I continued to have such dreams, I continued to sleep with men.
Whenever I went somewhere and was approached by poor or low class men,
I would reject them because I considered myself a high-class lady as I appeared in my dreams.
He said that the more he dreamt of being this lady, the deeper he got into doing these actions.
He even saw himself as a queen - a very honourable queen.
When poor men approached him to sleep with him,
he had no interest in them because he felt he is worthy of sleeping with big men
as he used to see himself as a big queen in his dreams.
So, we can understand exactly what the man of God said when he said spirit of man,
and how this evil spirit entered our brother right from that tender age of 10 years old.
Tell us, how did you find yourself to be here in The SCOAN?
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
The lady, Mary, asked me why I was doing what was not pleasing to God.
She advised me to change, that I should tune to a station called Emmanuel TV
and even to leave it on while I slept through the night.
He said that he met with one lady called Mary. And this lady told him, "Why are you doing
these abominable acts? You should change your habit and be in a masculine way - the way God created you".
The lady advised him to start watching Emmanuel TV.
He got a decoder and put on the channel so he could start watching it.
Can you describe for us again, what happened in the service, what was going through your mind
at that moment when it was the time of prophecy?
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
I was disturbed in my heart and I would sit down whenever Prophet T.B. Joshua prayed.
He prayed for other people and when he moved away from me, my heart felt very happy.
He said that when the man of God was on the pulpit, whenever he was praying or doing prophecy,
his charisma was very low. He never felt interested. He would just sit down.
Whenever the man of God would leave the pulpit and go out for a moment,
his spirit would be very happy.
But immediately the man of God came back, that's when he would start feeling agitated
and very uninterested in the service. He would just be sitting down.
When he came back the second time, that was when the spirit strangled me.
When the Prophet prayed and turned to my direction, that was when the arrow struck me.
He said that immediately the man of God pointed out his case and faced him,
the situation got even worse.
He had the feeling of being strangled, something was poking him and there was a very big battle.
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
Later, the Prophet said, "You", and I ducked down on my chair to hide.
He repeated the prophecy and I hid again.
I told my neighbour that the Prophet was talking to him but insisted that it was for me.
Prophet T.B. Joshua beckoned me to come and I found myself moving towards him.
The spirit continued to strangle and torment me as if it wanted to take my life.
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
He said that the thing which was hooking him - it was so serious to such an extent that he felt as if
his life was coming to an end.
Immediately the man of God started talking to him, he felt like hiding
and told his neighbour, "The man of God is speaking to you; he is not speaking to me".
He was tapping his neightbour that the prophecy which the man of God was giving was not referring to him.
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
Since the time he prayed for me, I have been well. I am free.
He said that immediately the man of God talked to him and prayed for him, he now feels very free.
That urge is gone, and he feels like a normal healthy human being.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
We just want to be clear, brother. Ever since the prophecy last week and the prayer you received in the
the name of Jesus Christ, how has your life changed?
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
Now, I have changed a lot. I even have affection for ladies.
Previously, I was not like that but now, I don't like men anymore; I just see them as my friends.
He said that his life has changed dramatically. He doesn't have the urge for men anymore.
He even has affection for women now.
Whenever he is around men, he just feels like being with friends with whom he can share words of advice and the like.
He no longer has the urge for men.
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
When I sleep, I no longer dream those dreams I used to have.
Now, I dream things pertaining to God and if I have any fear, I pray with Psalm 51.
He said that his dreams have totally changed.
He doesn't see himself doing all these strange things he was doing in the past.
He just dreams of things that pertain to God.
His desire to read the Bible has grown stronger.
Whenever he faces a challenge, his heart will just point him to go and read the Bible.
He loves to read and pray with the psalm of repentance - Psalm 51, whenever he faces any challenge.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
This is truly the evidence that the spirit of man has completely left our brother's life
after the word of prophecy and deliverance in the name of Jesus Christ.
Brother, what is your advice to our viewers all over the world?
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
This problem is very bad and I advise my fellows that it is possible to stop.
They should depend on God and involve Him in every matter and they will succeed as I have.
He said that what he was doing was very bad.
He is advising his fellows that this thing is possible to abort and to leave it. It is possible to be delivered.
They should just look onto God. At the end of the day, God will transform their lives
and give them a new hope, a new life in the name of Jesus Christ.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ!
Indeed, only God Almighty could bring about such a transformation and we give all glory to God Almighty.
Brother, just describe to us: As the man of God gave that prophecy
and we saw you come forward, holding your neck, what was happening at that moment?
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
That spirit was strangling me as if it wanted to kill me.
When I wanted to move towards the Prophet, it would pull me back or in a different direction.
He said that the moment the man of God pointed to him,
something very strong hooked him by the throat and poked him in the chest.
When he moved towards the man of God, immediately the thing got stronger
and was pulling him back; it didn't want him to go towards that direction.
He felt like his life was just going to end; he was going to die.
This is indeed the power of God that exposed the evil spirits in the life of our brother - the spirit of man -
and sent it out. Today, by the grace of God, we have heard it from our brother that
since last week, he has been living a free life, a normal life.
He has no affection or urge for his fellow men. Indeed, he said he now has affection for females
as it is intended by God Almighty. We give all the glory to God for his wonderful deliverance in Jesus' name.
One more time, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)
We just want to use this opportunity as well to use the case of our brother
as an advice to the world. The man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, always says
that as Christians we must know that we must love sinners but hate sin.
That is, we should hate the act but not the person.
Because if you don't love people, if you don't love someone like our brother,
how will we be actually able to help them. You cannot help people that you hate.
In fact, it is only through love that we can help because there is no love through hatred.
It is genuine help that can bring about love.
If someone like Prophet T.B. Joshua did not show love, he would not be able to help people like our brother here.
He came all the way from Tansania here to Nigeria.
If he, Prophet T.B. Joshua, did not take care of this brother, did not accommodate him,
did not feed him, then he would not be in the position to help him
as we are seeing him sharing his testimony right now.
Viewers all over the world, know that hate cannot help anyone. It is love that can help.
This is why Jesus Christ gave the instruction, "Love your neighbour as yourself".
Our Lord Jesus Christ also further stated that the sun reigns on both the righteous and the unrighteousness.
The meaning of this is that if you only love those that love you, of what benefit is it to you.
The purpose for that our Lord Jesus Christ came into this world was love.
Even those who hate you, love all. Not just those who love you.
Therefore, it is by loving those who hate you that you love our Lord Jesus Christ
and demonstrate His love in the world. So, once again, this is a case example that we believe
serves as a lesson to our viewers all over the world. Let us love the sinner but hate the sin.
That is, hate the act, not the person.
We thank Jesus Christ that right now our brother is free and when the Son of God sets you free,
you are free indeed. One more time, let us put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Mr Patrick James (Prophecy Testimony)